ircwash.org 2019-06-02

# Privacy statement :: IRC

### Use of personal data

IRC attaches great importance to the adequate protection of your personal data. IRC handles personal data carefully and confidentially, it will be protected from loss, unauthorised access, or theft and will not be kept any longer than is necessary.

IRC does not knowingly collect online personal information from children under the age of 16. If you are a parent or guardian of a minor under the age of 16 and believe that he or she has disclosed personal information to us, please contact us.

IRC will not use any personal data collected on this site for any purpose other than that specifically stated. IRC does not sell or pass on personal contact details to any organisation. If you agree to receive, or sign up for, further information from IRC, you will be offered an opportunity to unsubscribe from that communication. IRC will discontinue sending this information on your first request.

If IRC wishes to process personal data for another purpose, IRC will provide you with information regarding the other purpose of that further processing as well as other relevant information.

### Information collection, use and sharing

IRC is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via the contact form. We will not sell or rent this information to anyone. IRC will only use the information to respond to you regarding the reason you contacted us.

### Your access to and control over information

You can contact us via email ([info@ircwash.org](mailto:info@ircwash.org) with as  **subject** : My personal data) at any time to ask us the following:

  * See what data we have about you, if any
  * Change/correct any data we have about you
  * Have us delete any data we have about you (including photos on the website)
  * Express any concern you have about our possible use of your data

We must provide the information free of charge unless we deem the request to be unfounded or excessive. In this event, we will explain why we have decided not to take action upon your request. To protect the confidentiality of your information, we will ask you to verify your identity before proceeding with any request you make under this Privacy Notice.

If you feel that your data has not been handled correctly, or you are unhappy with our response to any requests you have made to us regarding the use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the [Dutch Data Protection Authority](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/en/contact-dutch-dpa/contact-us).

### Security

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit information via our website, your information is protected both online and offline.

Wherever we collect information, that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. We have secured this website with the HTTPS protocol (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure), a standard web communication protocol that encrypts and decrypts a message for online transmission.

While we use encryption to protect information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for instance answer your query) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

### Cookies

In offering its services, IRC uses ‘cookies’. Cookies are small temporary files that are stored on the hard drive of the computer. These cookies do not contain any personal data, are not (directly) traceable to a living natural person, and are only used to make the website more easy to use. They are used to remember information between successive requests for a webpage. This site uses cookies only to facilitate browsing the website and to analyse the usage of the website.

We are not responsible for cookies placed by external parties such as Drupal (website software), SoundCloud, YouTube etc. We refer to the data protection and privacy practices of these organisations as published on their websites.

### Usage statistics

IRC collects standard usage statistics (using Google Analytics) on its web server. This does not include personal data, but rather information which assists IRC in assessing the general usage patterns of its site and to optimise the use of its website. This information may include the IP address of your computer. IRC will not attempt to trace that IP address to you personally, nor will it allow that information to be tracked by outside agencies. The data collected via Google Analytics are deleted at regular intervals.

### Blocking or deleting cookies

The majority of web browsers (Firefox, Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Opera, Safari etc.) will allow you to block / delete cookies from your device via your browser settings. We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at the [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) website which offers guidance for all modern browsers.

For information on how to opt-out of cookies set by Google Analytics, please visit the following link: “[Cookies Set by Google Analytics and Google Analytics Privacy Overview](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=nl&ref_topic=2919631)”

Mobile phone users may have to refer to their handset manual.

### When registering for an online course

When you choose to follow a specific free online training course on the IRC Moodle website. For you to be able to sign in, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information. We may collect the following types of information:

  * First Name
  * Surname
  * Email address
  * Job title
  * Company
  * Work Address
  * Work City
  * Country
  * Work Postal Code

How will we use your data?

  * Your learner data (first/last name and email) will be stored on IRC’s Learner Management System (LMS) to enable you to access the online learning service, complete courses, answer questionnaires, access resources, record learning progress, download personalised certificates and attend in forums and discussions.
  * To notify you about changes to our service and trainings.

You will have three months to complete the online training course. After four months, access to the courses and training service will no longer be available and we will:

  * Permanently delete your account, personal information, your learner data, your training history and certificates from the LMS.
  * Retain your key contact details on the internal CRM system.

This website is governed by Dutch law and [EU privacy regulations](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en).

This privacy statement has been updated on 12 June 2018.
